Declan Toohey

Adelaide, Beverley 5009 Phone: +61 431 490 343 Email: djtoohey@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/DeclanToohey

GitHub: https://github.com/djtoohey/ Portfolio: https://djtoohey.github.io/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for technology and a history in game development. Efficient problem solver and open minded to engage more with the problem at hand and develop a product that takes on new ideas as it is being developed. At current employment, known for reliability and helpfulness, always available to cover shifts and do additional areas of work to assist the entire team is keeping up to standard and speed.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C#, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, JSON, ActionScript

Applications: jQuery, Node.js, Express, React, GIT & GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB, Unity5.0

Projects

Music Quiz App

https://github.com/marasinipradeep/music-app/ https://marasinipradeep.github.io/music-app/

- A short quiz that returns a song once completed based off of user answers
- Made the initial wireframe, researched different music API, added functionality between the user's answers and what song would be returned
- Made using HTML, CSS, Javascript, ¡Query and MusixMatch API

Professor Oak's Pokemon Love Calculator

https://github.com/thomasmaglaris/Professor-Oak-s-Pokemon-Love-Calculator/ https://powerful-mountain-92684.herokuapp.com/

- Users input two names and it returns a compatibility rating as well as a pokemon with a pun/joke based off of the pokemon
- Handled the routing of pages, API and front end to back end calls and backend JS
- Made using HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node JS, Express, MySQL, UniRest, Sequelize, Love Calculator API and Pokemon API

inTune for Spotify

https://djtoohey-intune.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/djtoohey/inTune

- Users input their Spotify details and it returns a playlist of mutually liked songs
- Made entirely by me!
- Made using MERN stack, Spotify API, various Spotify API NPM packages, Passport, Bulma, Axios and Request

Experiences

Team Member / Shift Supervisor KFC

2018 – Present Adelaide, SA

Applied communication skills to both other team members and customers, handled customer complaints, adopted an understanding of safety protocols, handled money, developed teamwork skills with others to achieve speed and accuracy and utilised being able to see customer dissatisfaction before it could rise to a higher up.

Key Accomplishments:

- In under 3 years, was able to go from never worked before to being a shift supervisor
- Multiple recognitions through internal communications and in person meetings

Admin Assistant Mk2 Recruitment

2019– 2019 Adelaide, SA

Answering phone calls and redirecting to the appropriate employee, scheduled interviews for potential work, set up employee personnel pages (data entry, calling up employees to ensure data was up to date), communicated with other employees to determine where to send special case employee calls and ensured all timesheets for the week were present and if not followed up to find them.

Tutor 2017-2018 High School Adelaide, SA

Educated fellow students in IT and religious studies, ensured that assignments were done by the due date and done to a good standard, assisted when they needed further explanation of a concept, and approachable for other students when the teacher was unavailable.

Education

Certificate of Completion for Full Stack Web Development: University of Adelaide, Adelaide, SA (2020)

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelors of Information Technology: University of South Australia, Adelaide, SA (2019) Did one semester of the degree, in that time I did; Programming and Problem Solving (Python) [HD], Networking Fundamentals (CISCO Netacad) [D], Information Technology Fundamentals (History of computers, learned some machine code) [D], Design Thinking and Digital Innovation (Identifying a problem in a community and coming up with a digital innovation solution) [D]. Stopped doing the degree as it was not what I was looking for at the time, and went on to time the Full Stack Web Development program.

Certificate III in Information, Digital media and Technology: Academy of Interactive Entertainment, Adelaide, SA (2017)

Certificate III completed during Year 11, learned the basics of programming through the use of C# and the Unity 5 game engine, publish games for web environments, downloadable executable and mobile platforms. Once complete all necessary tasks, investigated into SteamVR development and made a basic throwing a ball into a goal game.